# **Ashutosh Patel**

House no.-84 Sector-17A Sukhrali, Gurgaon patelahutosh1361994@gmail.com

Phone: +91-7011747626

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

4+ years of experience in mechanical design, SPLM software, CAD/CAM, mold design, part design. I have good communication, presentation and interpersonal skills. I am involved in all mechanical CAD/CAM processes and presales/post sales. I also have experience in the tool room and plastics process.

#### **SKILLS**

- Part design : Automotive part design (NX) ,(Solid edge)
- Mold design : Mold wizard/Manually (NX), Manually (Solid edge)
- Manufacturing(CAM): (NX), Power mill
- 5-axis, 4-axis, Turning(CAM): NX
- Mold: Plastics mold assembly and troubleshooting.
- Development : Development of jigs and fixture for automobile industry
- Sales: Involve in Presales/Post sales, Customer handling, Customer Training/Support.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Sun vacuum pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon, India

Tool-Room Engineer

April2016 – May2018

- Worked in Tool-room, Handling all CAM processes, troubleshooting and assembly of plastics mold.
- Involved in jig and fixtures design for Automobile industry.

## Parametric designs & solutions, Gurgaon, India

Senior Application Engineer

May2018 - present

- Handling CAD/CAM mechanical software implementation, customer training, customer support.
- Handling Mold design, part design, Manufacturing, 3-Axis CAM, 4-Axis CAM, 5-Axis CAM, Turning CAM.
- Handling pre-sales/post-sales activity.

## **EDUCATION**

Central Institute of plastics engineering & technology (CIPET), Jaipur, Rajasthan

Aug 2013 - May2016

Diploma: Plastics mold design

(plastics/mechanical) Percentage: 80.37 %

Bal bharti inter college, UP BOARD, ORAI, (UP)

Mar 2011 - Mar 2012

Mar 2012- May2015

Degree : UP BOARD (XII) Percentage:

65.60 %

Bachelor in science, Bundelkhand university

Degree : (P,C,M) Percentage: 58 %

## **PROJECTS**

#### Schneider prototype

Skills used: NX-CAD & CAM

Implemented 7-Axis Machine kit according to machine(DMG kit), simulate machine according to software(automation work)

### SuperMac pvt. Ltd.

Skills used: NX-CAM & Post builder

Input all kinematic data according to machine

And Developed

Postprocessor(4-Axis, Kafo machine).

#### Mother-son

Skills used: NX-CAD CAM(Post builder)

Developed post processor for

HAAS, MITSUBISHI, HARMLE, FANUC.

Help to develop mold by the help of MOLD WIZARD.

Escorts Itd.(design and development)

Skills used: Solid edge

Help to develop parts of crane and tractor.

#### Havells Itd.

Skills used: NX-CAD, NX-CAM, SOLID EDGE Implemented CAM setup according to machine Guwahati, haridwar, Sahibabad, Faridabad, baddi plant, help to develop mold for switches and mcb.

## Hema Engineering (former OMAX).

Skills used: NX-CAD CAM

Implemented nx cad and cam software give needed training and develop cam part as per requirement

## Life long pvt. Ltd.

Skills used: NX-CAD(MOLD WIZARD)

Develop mold as per requirements and provide required training.